# Emad Ehsanrad

Senior Software Engineer

✓ emad.ehsanrad@gmail.com in /in/emadehsanrad

 $\mathbf{J} + 98(939)269 - 3405$ (CodeWithEmad

# SUMMARY

Software engineer with 6+ years of diverse software engineering experience with specialties in software architecture design, infrastructure operation, and backend development. Passionate about contributing to open-source and tech communities by sharing knowledge and experience. Very interested in seeing and experiencing new environments and technologies and getting things DONE.

### EXPERIENCE

## • Notion Wave Software Engineer Dubai, UAE

February 2022 - Present

- Led the design and development of edSPIRIT, a scalable SaaS Open edX platform, resulting in a client base of more than 200, boosting overall growth.
- o Architected and implemented a new billing and subscription system, enhancing the client's user experience and boosting the platform's reliability.
- Built a custom solution for scaling down Kubernetes clusters to zero pods, slashing operational costs by 30%.
- Designed a structured onboarding program for new engineers, ensuring smooth transition & clear goals.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and test web applications using Python and Django.
- Avid Arvand Fullstack Python developer Tehran, Iran

May 2019 - February 2022

- Implemented multi-tenancy support, enhancing scalability and reducing operational costs by 20%.
- Integrated authentication and other services with SSO with Keycloak, enhancing security and system efficiency.
- Automated EPUBs with web scraper, saving our team months & securing a partnership with Rice University.
- Configured and managed CI/CD pipelines, improving application delivery time.
- Empowered team with Python/Django workshops, boosting skill development.
- InstructHub Backend Developer Tehran, Iran

September 2017 - January 2019

- o Architected and deployed scalable, high-availability systems on AWS utilizing EC2, S3, RDS, and VPC.
- Worked closely with stakeholders to gather and analyze requirements for developing software solutions tailored to specific business needs.
- Built backend logic for coding exercises and auto-grading systems, applying algorithms to evaluate code submissions in real-time.
- $\circ\,$  Achieved 94% test coverage by increasing the use of automated testing.
- Set up error logging and monitoring using tools like Sentry and ELK Stack, ensuring rapid issue identification.

#### EDUCATION

# Kermanshah University of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Telecommunication Engineering

September 2012 - September 2016

## Certificates

Machine Learning with Python, Coursera

September 2024

Kermanshah, Iran

LPIC 1 & 2, Go To Class

August 2022

## SKILLS

Languages: Python, Typescript, Dart, SQL

Tools: Kubernetes, Docker, GitLab CI

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB Frameworks: Django, Flask, NextJS, Flutter

LANGUAGES

**German**: Elementary proficiency (A1) **English**: Full professional proficiency (C1)